Sugarcane is a documentary film directed by Emily Kassie.
An investigation into abuse and missing children at an Indian residential school
in Canada ignites a reckoning on the nearby Sugarcane Reserve.
Self, played by Julian Brave NoiseCat.
Self, played by Willie Sellars.
Self, played by Charlene Belleau.
Self, played by Ed Archie Noisecat.
Self, played by Chief Willie Sellars.
Sugarcane is a 2024 documentary film, directed by Julian Brave NoiseCat and
Emily Kassie and produced by Emily Kassie and Kellen Quinn.
It follows an investigation into the Canadian Indian residential school system,
igniting a reckoning in the lives of survivors and descendants.
It had its world premiere at the Sundance Film Festival on January 20,
2024 where it won the Grand Jury award for Directing.
It was theatrically released in limited engagements in the United States and Canada  on August 9, 2024, before gradually expanding to other cities
starting August 16, by National Geographic Documentary Films through Variance Films in the United States and Films We Like in Canada.
It received critical acclaim and won the award for Best
Documentary at the National Board of Review.
At the 97th Academy Awards, it was nominated for the
Best Documentary Feature Film award.
The film explores themes of child abuse, somber, bitter, tragic, urgent.